Guide to the Rand School of Social Science Records TAM.007
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Series IV: Financial Records, 1912-1955
  - Audits and Treasurer Reports, 1929 (Box 38, Folder 17)
  - Audits and Treasurer Reports, 1930 (Box 38, Folder 18)
  - Audits and Treasurer Reports, 1931 (Box 38, Folder 19)
  - Audits and Treasurer Reports, 1932-1933 (Box 38, Folder 20)
  - Audits and Treasurer Reports, 1934 (Box 38, Folder 21)
  - Audits and Treasurer Reports, 1935 (Box 38, Folder 22)
  - Audits and Treasurer Reports, 1936 (Box 38, Folder 23)
  - Audits and Treasurer Reports, 1937 (Box 38, Folder 24)
  - Audits and Treasurer Reports, 1938 (Box 38, Folder 25)
  - Audits and Treasurer Reports, 1939 (Box 38, Folder 26)
  - Audits and Treasurer Reports, 1940-1941 (Box 39, Folder 1)
  - Audits and Treasurer Reports, 1941-1942 (Box 39, Folder 2)
  - Audits and Treasurer Reports, 1942-1943 (Box 39, Folder 3)
  - Audits and Treasurer Reports, 1943-1944 (Box 39, Folder 4)
  - Audits and Treasurer Reports, 1944-1945 (Box 39, Folder 5)
  - Audits and Treasurer Reports, 1945-1946 (Box 39, Folder 6)
  - Audits and Treasurer Reports, 1946-1947 (Box 39, Folder 7)
  - Audits and Treasurer Reports, 1947-1948 (Box 39, Folder 8)
  - Audits and Treasurer Reports, 1948-1949 (Box 39, Folder 9)
  - Audits and Treasurer Reports, 1949-1950 (Box 39, Folder 10)
  - Audits and Treasurer Reports, 1950-1951 (Box 39, Folder 11)
  - Audits and Treasurer Reports, 1951-1952 (Box 39, Folder 12)
  - Audits and Treasurer Reports, 1952-1953 (Box 39, Folder 13)
  - Audits and Treasurer Reports, 1953-1954 (Box 39, Folder 14)
  - Audits and Treasurer Reports, 1954-1955 (Box 39, Folder 15)
  - Audits and Treasurer Reports, undated (Box 39, Folder 16)
  - Bequests & Wills, 1943-1954 (Box 39, Folder 17)
    Film R-7124, Reel 46: Frame XIII:D:3
  - Concert Benefits, 1932 (Box 39, Folder 18)
    Film R-7124, Reel 46: Frame XIII:D:4
  - Concert Benefits, 1933 (Box 39, Folder 19)
  - Concert Benefits, 1934 (Box 39, Folder 20)
  - Concert Benefits, 1935 (Box 39, Folder 21)
  - Concert Benefits, 1936 (Box 39, Folder 22)
  - Concert Benefits, 1938 (Box 39, Folder 23)
  - Concert Benefits, 1942 (Box 39, Folder 24)
  - Concert Benefits, 1947 (Box 39, Folder 25)
  - Concert Benefits, 1948 (Box 39, Folder 26)
  - Concert Benefits, 1949 (Box 39, Folder 27)
  - Concert Benefits, 1950 (Box 39, Folder 28)
  - Concert Benefits, 1951 (Box 39, Folder 29)
  - Concert Benefits, 1951 (Box 39, Folder 30)
  - Concert Benefits, 1952 (Box 39, Folder 31)
  - Concert Benefits, 1952 (Box 39, Folder 32)
  - Concert Benefits, 1952 (Box 40, Folder 1)
  - Concert Benefits, 1952 (Box 40, Folder 2)
  - Concert Benefits, 1953 (Box 40, Folder 3)
  - Concert Benefits, 1955 (Box 40, Folder 4)
  - Contributors to Sustaining Fund, 1926-1931 (Box 40, Folder 5)
    Film R-7124, Reel 46: Frame XIII:D:5
  - One Third of a Century Fund, Aug 22, 1939-May 13, 1940 (Box 40, Folder 6)
    Film R-7124, Reel 46: Frame XIII:D:6
- Series V: Rand School Bookstore Records, 1922-1956
  The Rand School Bookstore records, consisting of six subject files, include reports and plans of the bookstore, financial records, job applications, printed catalogues of books, advertising flyers and brochures, and correspondence. The items within these files are arranged' in chronological order., with undated items placed at the end of the file. Of particular interest in this series is the correspondence (XIII:E:6). The letters contained in this file offer a unique insight into the operating procedures of the bookstore and the people who transacted business with the store.
  - Reports and Plans of the Bookstore, ca.Feb 29, 1944-1952, undated (Box 40, Folder 7)
    Film R-7124, Reel 46: Frame XIII:E:1
  - Financial Records, Nov 1, 1922-Sep 30, 1951, undated (Box 40, Folder 8)
    Film R-7124, Reel 46: Frame XIII:E:2
  - Job Applications, Sep 29, 1942-October 6, 1942, undated (Box 40, Folder 9)
    Film R-7124, Reel 46: Frame XIII:E:3
  - Printed Catalogues of Books, undated (Box 40, Folder 10)
    Film R-7124, Reel 46: Frame XIII:E:4
  - Advertising Flyers and Brochures, 1922-1946, undated (Box 40, Folder 11)
    Film R-7124, Reel 46: Frame XIII:E:5
  - Correspondence, May 21, 1938-Jun 4, 1940 (Box 40, Folder 12)
    Film R-7124, Reel 47: Frame XIII:E:6
  - Correspondence, May 21, 1938-Jun 4, 1940 (Box 40, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence, Mar 19, 1943-Oct 29, 1944 (Box 40, Folder 14, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence, Jan 4, 1945-Mar 29, 1945 (Box 40, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence, Apr 1945-Jun 21, 1945 (Box 40, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence, Jul 9, 1945-Sep 28, 1945 (Box 40, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence, Oct 3, 1945-Dec 29, 1945 (Box 41, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, Jan 1, 1946-Feb 28, 1946 (Box 41, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, Mar 1, 1946-Apr 30, 1946 (Box 41, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, May 1, 1946-Jun 30, 1946 (Box 41, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, Jul 1, 1946-Aug 31, 1946 (Box 41, Folder 5)
    Film R-7124, Reel 48: Frame XIII:E:6
  - Correspondence, Sep 1, 1946-Dec 24, 1946 (Box 41, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, Jan 3, 1947-Jun 30, 1947 (Box 41, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, Jul 1, 1947-Jul 29, 1947 (Box 41, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, Oct 1947-Dec 29, 1947 (Box 41, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, Jan 1948-Mar 30, 1948 (Box 41, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, Jan 1948-Mar 30, 1948 (Box 41, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, Apr 1, 1948-Jun 30, 1948 (Box 42, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, Jul 1948-Sep 29, 1948 (Box 42, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, Oct 2, 1948-Dec 30, 1948 (Box 42, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, Jan 3, 1949-Jun 30, 1949 (Box 42, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, Jul 1, 1949-Dec 29, 1949 (Box 42, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, Jan 3, 1950-Dec 27, 1950 (Box 42, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, Jan 15, 1951-Nov 28, 1951 (Box 42, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, Jan 26, 1952-Nov 23, 1953 (Box 42, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, Feb 9, 1954-Jan 18, 1956 (Box 42, Folder 9)
  - Auditor's Reports, 1922-1924, 1931, 1938-1939 (Box 42, Folder 10)
  - Financial Records: Report for Period (four copies), Aug 1, 1939-Mar 3, 1941 (Box 42, Folder 11)
  - Lists of Books & Pamphlets Stocked, undated (Box 42, Folder 12)
  - Mailing Lists, 1955, undated (Box 42, Folder 13)
  - Lists of Labor Magazines and Newspapers (correspondence lists), undated (Box 42, Folder 14)
  - List of Book Orders by Customers, Mar 11, 1952-Mar 16, 1954 (Box 42, Folder 15)
- Series VI: Publications, 1906-1955
  - Subseries VIA: Correspondence and Reports, 1912-1953
    The correspondence and reports part contains three files which pertain to the Labor Research Department (XIII:F:1:1), the American Labor Archive and Research Institute (XIII:F:1:2), and the Institute of Social Studies (XIII:F:1:3). The papers within these files are arranged in chronological order, with undated items placed at the end of the file. The two most interesting files in this part are those of the Labor Research Department and the American Labor Archive and Research Institute. The Labor Research Department file contains numerous reports on American labor issues and the Department's operations. The correspondence in this file primarily consists of reviews of The American Labor Year Book.Among the principal correspondents in this file are Alexander Trachtenberg, Feliks Gross, Harry W. Laidler, Solon De Leon, Max Nomad, Mark Starr, Upton Sinclair, and James Oneal.
    The American Labor Archive and Research Institute was established in 1941 for the purpose of preserving documents which related to the European and American labor movements. The correspondence in the American Labor Archive file pertains to the activities of the Archive's director, Boris Nicolaevsky. There is also an interesting report in this file entitled, "Jewish Problems in the American Trade Union Press, 1944-1945." This report was prepared by the American Labor Archive staff for the Jewish Labor Committee
    - Labor Research Department, Dec 31, 1912-[1933], undated (Box 43, Folder 1)
      Film R-7124, Reel 49: Frame XIII:F:1:1
    - Labor Research Department, Dec 31, 1912-[1933], undated (Box 43, Folder 2)
    - American Labor Archive and Research Institute, ca.1941-Feb 16, 1951 (Box 43, Folder 3)
      Film R-7124, Reel 49: Frame XIII:F:1:2
    - Institute of Social Studies, Jan 3, 1950-1952 (Box 43, Folder 4)
      Film R-7124, Reel 49: Frame XIII:F:1:3
    - Institute of Social Studies, Jan 3, 1950-1952 (Box 43, Folder 5)
    - Institute of Social Studies, ca.1953-1955, undated (Box 43, Folder 6)
    - Institute of Social Studies, ca.1953-1955, undated (Box 43, Folder 7)
  - Subseries VIB: Pamphlets and Books, 1914-1954
    The pamphlets and books part of the publications series consists of 83 pamphlets and one book. These items are arranged in alphabetical order according to the author's last name or the title of the publication. Some of the topics discussed in the pamphlets include the Taft Hartley Law, the Lusk Committee's investigation of the Rand School, socialist theory, race prejudice, the objectives of organized labor, the New York City socialist aldermen, the Seabury investigation, public ownership, the Moscow Trials, the rise of totalitarian regimes in the 1930s, the Russian Revolution, militarism, the American Labor Party, the Austrian Civil War, and the "Popular Front" issue. Many of these pamphlets were written by such prominent figures as David P. Berenberg, August Claessens, Evans Clark, Max Eastman, James T. Farrell, Morris Hillquit, Herbert Morrison, Scott Nearing, James Oneal, and August Tyler. The only book in this part is The American Labor Who's Whowhich was edited by Solon De Leon in 1925 (XIII:F:2:27). This reference work, which was published under the auspices of the Labor Research Department, is a compilation of brief biographical sketches of prominent American labor leaders in the post World War I era. A full bibliographical citation for each item in this part is located in the complete reel list for this collection.
    - Adler, Friedrich. Democracy and Revolution. New York: Rand School Press, 23pp., 1934 (Box 43, Folder 1, Folder 8)
      Film R-7124, Reel 49: Frame XIII:F:2:1
    - Ashe, David I. and Rifkin, George. The Taft­ Hartley Law. How It Affects Unions and Workers. New York: Rand School Press, 32pp., 1947 (Box 43, Folder 8)
      Film R-7124, Reel 49: Frame XIII:F:2:2
    - Barres, Maurice. Les Diverse Familles. Spirituelles De La France: Les Israelites. New York:-Rand School of Social Science, 25pp., 1943 (Box 43, Folder 8)
      Film R-7124, Reel 49: Frame XIII:F:2:3
    - Berenberg, David P. America at the Crossroads. New York: Rand School Press, 95pp., 1934 (Box 43, Folder 8)
      Film R-7124, Reel 49: Frame XIII:F:2:4
    - Berenberg, David P. Socialism. New York: Rand School of Social Science, 43pp., 1918 (Box 43, Folder 8)
      Film R-7124, Reel 49: Frame XIII:F:2:5
    - Berenberg, David P. Socialist Fundamentals. Second Edition. New York: Rand School Press, 118pp., 1935 (Box 43, Folder 9)
      Film R-7124, Reel 49: Frame XIII:F:2:6
    - Berenberg, David P. We The People. New York: Rand School Press, 14 pp., 1934 (Box 43, Folder 9)
      Film R-7124, Reel 49: Frame XIII:F:2:7
    - Berenberg, David P. A Worker's World. New York: Rand School Press, l6pp., 1931 (Box 43, Folder 9)
      Film R-7124, Reel 49: Frame XIII:F:2:8
    - The Case of the Rand School. New York: Rand School of Social Science, l7pp., Jul 26, 1919 (Box 43, Folder 9)
      Film R-7124, Reel 49: Frame XIII:F:2:9
    - The City for the Workers. New York: Rand School of Social Science, 30pp., Fall 1917 (Box 43, Folder 9)
      Film R-7124, Reel 49: Frame XIII:F:2:10
    - Claessens, August. The Democratic Way of Life. New York: Rand School Press, 30pp., 1940 (Box 43, Folder 9)
      Film R-7124, Reel 49: Frame XIII:F:2:11
    - Claessens, August. Essentials of Socialism. A Brief Exposition of the Principal Elements of Modern Socialism. New York: Rand School Press, l6pp., 1932 (Box 43, Folder 9)
      Film R-7124, Reel 49: Frame XIII:F:2:12
    - Claessens, August. Eugene Victor Debs. A Tribute. New York: Rand School Press, 19pp., 1946 (Box 43, Folder 10)
      Film R-7124, Reel 49: Frame XIII:F:2:13
    - Claessens, August. The Logic of Socialism. New York: Rand School of Social Science, 51pp., 1921 (Box 43, Folder 10)
      Film R-7124, Reel 49: Frame XIII:F:2:14
    - Claessens, August. Race Prejudice. A Description of the Various Factors in Racial Animosities, Discriminations, and Conflicts, and the Conditions Under Which These Antagonisms Are Increased or Eliminated. New York: Rand School Press, 48pp., 1943 (Box 43, Folder 10, Box 44, Folder 1)
      Film R-7124, Reel 49: Frame XIII:F:2:15
    - Claessens, August. Social Attitudes Towards War and Peace. New York: Rand School Press, 15pp., 1934 (Box 43, Folder 10)
      Film R-7124, Reel 49: Frame XIII:F:2:16
    - Claessens, August. A Manual for Socialist Speakers. A Brief Text Book on the Technique of Public Speaking and Socialist Propaganda Meetings. New York: Rand School Press, 32pp., 1933 (Box 44, Folder 1)
      Film R-7124, Reel 49: Frame XIII:F:2:17
    - Claessens, August. A Manual for Trade Union Speakers. A Brief Text Book on Public Speaking. New York: International Ladies' Garment Workers Union, Educational Department, 28pp., 1936 (Box 43, Folder 10)
      Film R-7124, Reel 49: Frame XIII:F:2:18
    - Claessens, August. A Manual for Trade Union Speakers. A Brief Text Book on Public Speaking. Revised Edition. New York: Rand School Press, 28pp., 1948 (Box 44, Folder 1)
      Film R-7124, Reel 49: Frame XIII:F:2:19
    - Claessens, August. Understanding the Worker. Problems of Labor Organizations Analyzed in the Light of Social Psychology. Backgrounds in Trade Union History. New York: Rand School Press, 60pp., 1954 (Box 44, Folder 1)
      Film R-7124, Reel 49: Frame XIII:F:2:20
    - Claessens, August. What Organized Labor Wants. A Popular Description of Trade Union Philosophy, Economics and Ideals. New York: Rand School Press, l9pp., 1937 (Box 44, Folder 1)
      Film R-7124, Reel 49: Frame XIII:F:2:21
    - Claessens, August. What Organized Labor Wants. A Popular Description of Trade Union Philosophy, Economics, and Ideals. Revised Edition. New York: Rand School Press, 22pp., 1950 (Box 44, Folder 1)
      Film R-7124, Reel 49: Frame XIII:F:2:22
    - Claessens, August, and Feigenbaum, William Morris. The Socialists in the New York Assembly. The Work of Ten Socialist Members During the Legislative Session of 1918. New York: Rand School of Social Science, 96pp. (Box 44, Folder 1)
      Film R-7124, Reel 49: Frame XIII:F:2:23
    - Claessens, August, and Jarvis, Rebecca E. ABC of Parlia­mentary Law. A Brief Handbook on Rules of Order for Meetings Adapted to the Needs of Labor Groups. New York: Rand School Press, 32 pp. 32pp. 1936 (Box 44, Folder 1)
      Film R-7124, Reel 49: Frame XIII:F:2:24
    - Clark, Evans. Facts and Fabrications about Soviet Russia. New York: Rand School of Social Science, 93pp., 1920 (Box 44, Folder 2)
      Film R-7124, Reel 49: Frame XIII:F:2:25
    - Clark, Evans, and Solomon, Charles. The Socialists in the New York Board of Aldermen. A Record of Six Months' Activity. New York: Rand School of Social Science, 48pp., 1918 (Box 44, Folder 2)
      Film R-7124, Reel 49: Frame XIII:F:2:26
    - De Leon, Solon, ed. The American Labor Who's Who. New York: Hanford Press, 374pp., 1925 (Box 44, Folder 3)
      Film R-7124, Reel 49: Frame XIII:F:2:27
    - De Witt, S.A. Rhapsodies in Red. Songs for the Social Revolution. New York: Rand School Press, 48pp., 1933 (Box 44, Folder 4)
      Film R-7124, Reel 49: Frame XIII:F:2:28
    - Eastman, Max. A Letter to Americans. New York: Rand School Press, l3pp., ca.1941 (Box 44, Folder 4)
      Film R-7124, Reel 49: Frame XIII:F:2:29
    - Farrell, James T. Truth and Myth About America. A Statement Against Dictatorship Of or Over the Proletariat, and offering a Democratic Change for Social Progress. New York: Rand School Press, l4pp., Oct 1949 (Box 44, Folder 4)
      Film R-7124, Reel 49: Frame XIII:F:2:30
    - Feigenbaum, William M. "Let Us Review The Scene." New York, 99pp., 1951 (Box 44, Folder 4)
      Film R-7124, Reel 49: Frame XIII:F:2:31
    - Fine, Nathan. The Collapse of the Seabury Investigation. New York: Rand School Press, 31pp., 1932 (Box 44, Folder 4)
      Film R-7124, Reel 49: Frame XIII:F:2:32
    - Friedman, Samuel H., comp. ed. Rebel Song Book. Eighty-seven Socialist and Labor Songs for Voice and Piano. New York: Rand School Press, 92pp., 1935 (Box 44, Folder 5)
      Film R-7124, Reel 49: Frame XIII:F:2:33
    - Hillquit, Morris. Present-Day Socialism. New York: Rand School of Social Science, 84pp., 1920 (Box 44, Folder 5)
      Film R-7124, Reel 49: Frame XIII:F:2:34
    - Hillquit, Morris. Socialism Summed Up. New York: Rand School of Social Science, 108pp., 1914 (Box 44, Folder 5)
      Film R-7124, Reel 49: Frame XIII:F:2:35
    - Laidler, Harry W. Public Ownership Throughout the World. A Survey of the Extent of Government Control and Operation. New York: Rand School of Social Science, 48pp., 1918 (Box 44, Folder 6)
      Film R-7124, Reel 49: Frame XIII:F:2:36
    - Lenin, Nikolai. The Soviets at Work. The International Position of the Russian Soviet Republic and the Fundamental Problems of the Socialist Revolution. New York: Rand School of Social Science, 48pp., 1918 (Box 44, Folder 6)
      Film R-7124, Reel 49: Frame XIII:F:2:37
    - Letter of an Old Bolshevik. The Key to the Moscow Trials. New York: Rand School Press, 62pp., 1937 (Box 44, Folder 6)
      Film R-7124, Reel 49: Frame XIII:F:2:38
    - Lilienthal, Meta Stern. From Fireside to Factory. New York: Rand School of Social Science, 66pp., 1916 (Box 44, Folder 6)
      Film R-7124, Reel 49: Frame XIII:F:2:39
    - Lilienthal, Meta Stern. Women of the Future. New York: Rand School of Social Science, 31pp., 1916 (Box 44, Folder 6)
      Film R-7124, Reel 49: Frame XIII:F:2:40
    - Lipschitz, Dr. Siegfried. Swastika Over Germany. New York: Rand School Press, 48pp., 1933 (Box 44, Folder 6)
      Film R-7124, Reel 49: Frame XIII:F:2:41
    - Lomonossoff, George V. Memoirs of the Russian Revolution. New York: Rand School of Social Science, 87pp., 1919 (Box 44, Folder 7)
      Film R-7124, Reel 50: Frame XIII:F:2:42
    - Marx, Karl and Engels, Friedrich Manifesto of the Communist Party. New York: Rand School of Social Science, 56pp, 1919 (Box 44, Folder 7)
      Film R-7124, Reel 50: Frame XIII:F:2:43
    - Miles. Socialism's New Beginning. A Manifesto from Underground Germany New York: Rand School Press, 148pp, 1934 (Box 44, Folder 7)
      Film R-7124, Reel 50: Frame XIII:F:2:44
    - Morrison, Herbert. An Easy Outline of Modern Socialism New York: Rand School Press, 29pp, ca.Apr 1936 (Box 45, Folder 1)
      Film R-7124, Reel 50: Frame XIII:F:2:45
    - Morrison, Herbert. An Easy Outline of Modern Socialism Second Edition. New York: Rand School Press, 30pp, 1940 (Box 45, Folder 1)
      Film R-7124, Reel 50: Frame XIII:F:2:46
    - 'Morrison, Herbert. A Labor Party Versus Fascism Exposing the Bankruptcy of Fascism. New York: Rand School Press, l6pp., 1936 (Box 45, Folder 1)
      Film R-7124, Reel 50: Frame XIII:F:2:47
    - Must We Arm? A Debate on the Question: Re­solved, That the Security of the Nation Requiresan Increase of the Military Force of the United States. For the Affirmative, Augustus P. Gardner, M.C. For the Negative, Morris Hillquit New York: Rand School of Social Science, 44pp, 1915 (Box 45, Folder 1)
      Film R-7124, Reel 50: Frame XIII:F:2:48
    - Naft, Stephen. 100 Questions to the Communists New York: Rand School Press, 25pp, 1939 (Box 45, Folder 1)
      Film R-7124, Reel 50: Frame XIII:F:2:49
    - Nearing, Scott. The American Empire. New York Rand School of Social Science, 266pp, 1921 (Box 45, Folder 1)
      Film R-7124, Reel 50: Frame XIII:F:2:50
    - Nearing, Scott. The Coal Question. Some Reasons Why It Is Pressing and Some Suggestions for Solving It. New York: Rand School of Social Science, 47pp., 1918 (Box 45, Folder 3)
      Film R-7124, Reel 50: Frame XIII:F:2:51
    - Nearing, Scott. The Debs Decision New York: Rand School of Social Science, 47pp, 1919 (Box 45, Folder 1)
      Film R-7124, Reel 50: Frame XIII:F:2:52
    - Nearing, Scott. Europe and the Next War New York: Rand School of Social Science, 32pp., 1920 (Box 45, Folder 2)
      Film R-7124, Reel 50: Frame XIII:F:2:53
    - Nearing, Scott. Europe in Revolution Second Edition. New York: Rand school of Social Science, 30pp, 1920 (Box 45, Folder 2)
      Film R-7124, Reel 50: Frame XIII:F:2:54
    - Nearing, Scott. The Great Madness. A Victory for the American Plutocracy New York: Rand School of Social Science, 44pp, 1917 (Box 45, Folder 2)
      Film R-7124, Reel 50: Frame XIII:F:2:55
    - Nearing, Scott. Labor and the League of Nations With the Full Text of the Revised Covenant of the League of Nations New York: Rand School of Social Science, 47pp., 1919 (Box 45, Folder 2)
      Film R-7124, Reel 50: Frame XIII:F:2:56
    - Nearing, Scott. The Menace of Militarism. An Analysis, A Criticism, A Protest and a Demand New York: Rand School of Social Science, 52pp., 1917 (Box 45, Folder 3)
      Film R-7124, Reel 50: Frame XIII:F:2:57
    - Nearing, Scott. The One Big Union of Business New York: Rand School of Social Science, 32pp, 1920 (Box 45, Folder 3)
      Film R-7124, Reel 50: Frame XIII:F:2:58
    - Nearing, Scott. Work and Pay New York: Rand School of Social Science, 51pp, 1917 (Box 45, Folder 3)
      Film R-7124, Reel 50: Frame XIII:F:2:59
    - Oneal, James. The American Labor Party: An Interpretation New York: Rand School Press, 14pp, ca.1936 (Box 45, Folder 3)
      Film R-7124, Reel 50: Frame XIII:F:2:60
    - Oneal, James. The Austrian Civil War New York: Rand School Press, 31pp., ca.1934 (Box 45, Folder 3)
      Film R-7124, Reel 50: Frame XIII:F:2:61
    - Oneal, James. Socialism versus Bolshevism New York: Rand School Press, 27pp, 1935 (Box 45, Folder 3)
      Film R-7124, Reel 50: Frame XIII:F:2:62
    - Oneal, James. The Workers in American History Fourth Edition. New York: Rand School of Social Science, 208pp, 1921 (Box 45, Folder 4)
      Film R-7124, Reel 50: Frame XIII:F:2:63
    - Panken, Jacob. Socialism for America New York: Rand School Press, l6pp, ca.1933 (Box 45, Folder 4)
      Film R-7124, Reel 50: Frame XIII:F:2:64
    - Renan, Ernest. Identite Originelle et Separation Graduelle du Judaisme et du Christianisme. New York: Rand School of Social Science, 26pp, 1943 (Box 45, Folder 4)
      Film R-7124, Reel 50: Frame XIII:F:2:65
    - Renan, Ernest. Le Judaisme Comme Race et Comme Religion. New York: Rand School of Social Science, 29pp, 1943 (Box 45, Folder 4)
      Film R-7124, Reel 50: Frame XIII:F:2:66
    - The Salaried Man. The Story, in Two Episodes, of an Every-Day Person New York: Rand School of Social Science, 24p, 1920 (Box 45, Folder 4)
      Film R-7124, Reel 50: Frame XIII:F:2:67
    - Schaffer, Louis. Stalin's Fifth Column on Broadway New York: Rand School Press, 31pp, 1940 (Box 45, Folder 5)
      Film R-7124, Reel 50: Frame XIII:F:2:68
    - Schapiro, Theodore. The Challenge of Workers' Education New York: Rand School of Social Science, 9pp, ca.1951 (Box 45, Folder 5)
      Film R-7124, Reel 50: Frame XIII:F:2:69
    - Scott Nearing's Address to the Jury New York: Rand School of Social Science, 30pp, ca.1919 (Box 45, Folder 5)
      Film R-7124, Reel 50: Frame XIII:F:2:70
    - Should Socialism Prevail? A Debate. New York: Rand School of Social Science, 47pp, 1916 (Box 45, Folder 5)
      Film R-7124, Reel 50: Frame XIII:F:2:71
    - Should the Workers Form a Political Party of Their Own? A Debate New York: Rand School Press, 31pp, 1932 (Box 45, Folder 5)
      Film R-7124, Reel 50: Frame XIII:F:2:72